Guide to the Dorothy Norman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Pre-1990 Acquisitions, 1908-1983; 2; 25.25; 28 boxes
  - Literary Manuscripts
    - Pucciani, Oreste F. "Walt Whitman and the Nineteenth Century", undated (Box 87)
    - Pucciani, Oreste F. Untitled poem, undated (Box 87)
    - Puma, Fernando. "A Time Builder", undated (Box 87)
    - Quinn, Kerker. "Egoists", undated (Box 87)
    - Rainer, Luise. Untitled, undated (Box 87)
    - Ravagli, Angelo. Untitled, undated (Box 87)
    - Read, Herbert. "Culture and Education", undated (Box 87)
    - Read, Herbert. "Power Politics and Human Values", 1946, undated (Box 87)
    - Reddick, Lawrence Dunbar. "Letters From the Jim Crow Army", undated (Box 87)
    - Reed, Edwin. "Twelve Novels", undated (Box 87)
    - Reis, Rebecca. "Are Civil Liberties Measurable And, If So, How?", undated (Box 87)
    - Rencontres internationales (1st: 1946: Geneva). L'esprit européen [par] Benda [et al.] Textes in-extenso des conférences et des entretiens., 1947; 8 (Box 87)
    - Replansky, Naomi. Poems, undated (Box 87)
    - Riesel, Victor. "June-December-1941", undated (Box 87)
    - Riesman, David. Unsorted writings, 1948-1958, undated (Box 87)
    - Riesman, Evelyn Thompson. "George Grosz", undated (Box 87)
    - Riley, Maude Kemper. "Alfred Stieglitz, Individualist", 1946 September (Box 88)
    - Rilke, Rainer Maria. Poems, undated (Box 88)
    - Rilke, Rainer Maria. Excerpts from the correspondence between Rilke and Lisa Heise, undated (Box 88)
    - Rimbaud, Arthur. "The Deserts of Love", undated (Box 88)
    - Roditi, Eduardo. "The Poetics of Fascism", undated (Box 88)
    - Rodman, Selden. "Ernst Toller", 1939? (Box 88)
    - Rolland, Romain. "The Flame of Spinoza," translated by Charles B. Anderson, undated (Box 88)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor. Untitled, undated (Box 88)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano). "Last Speech", undated (Box 88)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul. Enjoy Your Museum. Ic: Vincent Van Gogh, undated (Box 88)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul. "The Enormous Cummings", undated (Box 88)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul. "Grand Transformation Scene", undated (Box 88)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul. "The Henry James Revival", 1946 January 11 (Box 88)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul. "The Rimbaud Influence", 1944 December (Box 88)
    - Roskolenko, Harry. "Dedication", undated (Box 88)
    - Ross, Steven. Untitled, undated (Box 88)
    - Rosselli, Carlo. "From: The Journal of a Militiaman", undated (Box 88)
    - Rougemont, Denis de. "La fin du monde", 1946 June (Box 88)
    - Rousset, David. L'univers concentrationnaire, 1946, undated (Box 88)
    - Rugg, Harold. "The Voice of the Plastic Arts", undated (Box 88)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel. "The Amistad Mutiny", undated (Box 88)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel. "The Fear of Poetry", undated (Box 88)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel. "The Soul and the Body of John Brown", 1940 February (Box 88)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel. Poems, undated (Box 88)
    - Ryerson, Edward. Untitled, undated (Box 88)
    - Sacco, Nicola & Vanzetti, Bartolomeo. The Letters of Sacco and Vanzetti, 1930 (Box 88)
    - Sand, George. Excerpt of a letter from George Sand to Gustave Flaubert, undated (Box 88)
      Includes dust jacket of The George Sand, Gustave Flaubert Letters, translated by Aimée McKenzie.
    - Salvemini, Gaetano. "Italy and a Separate Peace", undated (Box 88)
    - Salvemini, Gaetano. "Mussolini's Foreign Policy", undated (Box 88)
    - Sanger, Margaret. "Birth Control Through the Ages", undated (Box 88)
    - Saroyan, William. "The Great American Goof", undated (Box 88)
    - Saroyan, William. "Two Stories", undated (Box 88)
    - Saroyan, William. "War and Sport Notes", undated (Box 88)
    - Sartre, Jean-Paul. The Respectful Prostitute, 1946, undated (Box 88)
    - Schneider, Jewell. "America is a Classless Society", undated (Box 88)
    - Schnitzler, Arthur. "Notes on War and Peace", 1915 January (Box 88)
    - Scholl, Harry. "Dad I've Been Drafted", undated (Box 88)
    - Schubart, William. "A Letter from London - 1941", 1941 June 20 (Box 88)
    - Schuman, William. "Musical Organizations in America", undated (Box 88)
    - Schwimmer, Rosika. "Rosika Schwimmer vs. United States of America", undated (Box 88)
    - Schwimmer, Rosika. "Union Now - For Peace of War?", undated (Box 88)
    - Seldes, Gilbert. "WQXR", 1938 January 20 (Box 88)
    - Seligmann, Herbert J. (Herbert Jacob). "Beyond Catastrophe", undated (Box 88)
    - Seligmann, Herbert J. (Herbert Jacob). "The Jew and Anti-Semitism", undated (Box 88)
    - Seligmann, Herbert J. (Herbert Jacob). "Observations On a Main Theme", undated (Box 88)
    - Seligmann, Herbert J. (Herbert Jacob). "Observations on Barbarism and its Alternative", undated (Box 88)
    - Selvin, Paul. "From California to Capodichino", undated (Box 88)
    - Sheyne, Melitta. Poems, undated (Box 88)
    - Siemes, S. J. "A Dangerous Lull", 1946 May 15 (Box 88)
    - Silone, Ignazio. "The Conditions Essential for Rebirth", undated (Box 88)
    - Silone, Ignazio. Fontamara, 1934 (Box 88)
    - Silone, Ignazio. "On the Dignity of the Human Intelligence", undated (Box 88)
    - Silone, Ignazio. The School for Dictators, undated (Box 88)
    - Silone, Ignazio. "Some Facts About My Life", undated (Box 88)
    - Sims, Margaret. "Poem", undated (Box 88)
    - Singer, Caroline. Race?, 1939, undated (Box 88)
    - Slochower, Harry. "Ernst Toller", undated (Box 88)
    - Smith, T. V. "On Behalf of Civil Liberty in Illinois", 1937-1938 (Box 88)
    - Smuts, Jan Christiaan. "Speech by Field Marshal J. C. Smuts Given Over the S.A.B.C. on His Return to the Union, 18th December 1946", undated (Box 88)
    - Spender, Stephen. "The Spiritual Future of Europe", undated (Box 89)
    - Spender, Stephen. Trial of a Judge, 1938 September 27 (Box 89)
    - Stark, Irwin. "Logistics", undated (Box 89)
    - Stark, Irwin. "The Refugee", undated (Box 89)
    - Stark, John. "Seventeen Years With Stieglitz", undated (Box 89)
    - Stecker, Jack. "Leborvay", undated (Box 89)
    - Steichen, Edward J. "Alfred Stieglitz", 1946 September (Box 89)
    - Stein, Gertrude. "The Mother of Us All", undated (Box 89)
    - Stein, Leo. Untitled, undated (Box 89)
    - Stiefel, Babette. Poems, 1948, undated (Box 89)
    - Stieglitz, Alfred. Unsorted writings, undated (Box 89)
    - Straight, Michael. "Address by Michael Straight, Washington Editor the New Republic, Delivered Before the Annual Dinner of Foreign Correspondents, New York City, Nov. 19, 1941" (Box 89)
    - Strand, Paul. "Alfred Stieglitz, 1864-1946", undated (Box 89)
    - Sullivan, Louis H., "Democracy (A Man Search)", 1908; 2 (Box 89)
      Given to Dorothy Norman by George Elmslie in 1940.
    - Swan, Emma. Poems, undated (Box 89)
    - Sykes, Gerald. "The Age of Fable", undated (Box 89)
    - Sykes, Gerald. "The First Step in Discovering a New World", undated (Box 89)
    - Sykes, Gerald. "From Letters: Pertaining to Death of Rosenfeld and Stieglitz", 1946 (Box 89)
    - Sykes, Gerald. "Introducing the Common Foe", undated (Box 89)
    - Sykes, Gerald. "Reveille", undated (Box 89)
    - Syrkus, Szymon. "Basic Outlines of Warsaw's Planning", undated (Box 89)
    - Sze, Mai-mai. "The Rock", undated (Box 89)
    - Tas, Jeanne. "A Tribute to Ibsen and Nazimova", undated (Box 89)
    - Taylor, Glen H. (Glen Hearst). "Creation of a World Republic", 1945 October 24 (Box 89)
    - Taylor, Harold. "Philosophical Aspects of the Harvard Report", undated (Box 89)
    - Thompson, Dorothy. "Address by Dorothy Thompson on the Occasion of the Testimonial Dinner Given in Her Honor by the American Committee for Christian German Refugees", 1939 January 24 (Box 89)
    - Tjader, Marguerite. "Dreiser's Last Visit to New York", undated (Box 89)
    - Tofel, Jennings. "Alfred Stieglitz", undated (Box 89)
    - Toller, Ernst. The Swallow Book, translated by Selden Rodman, excerpts, undated (Box 89)
    - Tolson, Melvin Beaunorus. "Dark Symphony", 1940 (Box 89)
    - Toomer, Jean. "A Double Portrait", undated (Box 89)
    - Toscanini, Arturo. "To the Milanese", 1945 May 5 (Box 89)
    - Tozier, Roy. "Christian-Front, Bund-Klan, Americanism", undated (Box 89)
    - Tozier, Roy. Untitled fragments, undated (Box 89)
    - Truman, Harry S. "The Text of President Truman's Message on Civil Rights", 1948 February 3 (Box 89)
    - Tucci, Niccolò. "Hey!", undated (Box 89)
    - Tully, Robert. "Strike", 1941 March (Box 89)
    - Uhse, Bodo. "Speech of Bodo Uhse at General Delegates Session 'Writers in Exile,' Third American Writer Congress", 1939 June 4 (Box 89)
    - United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities. (1945-1969). Hearings Regarding the Communist Infiltration of the Motion Picture Industry, 1947 (Box 89)
    - Vallentin, Antonina. Untitled, undated (Box 89)
    - Van Vechten, Carl. Untitled, 1947 February 26 (Box 89)
    - Varese, Edgard. "The Art-Science of Music Today", 1942 (Box 89)
    - Vico, Giambattista. Princìpi di scienza nuova, excerpts in English, undated (Box 89)
    - Viertel, Berthold. "Bertolt Brecht and Writing the Truth", undated (Box 89)
    - Vyshinsky, Andrey Yanuaryevich & Roosevelt, Eleanor. "Exchange Between Vishinsky and Eleanor Roosevelt at U.N.O. General Assembly on Propaganda in Camps for Displaced Persons and Refugees", undated (Box 89)
    - "Wage Negotiations Between International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, CIO, and General Motors Corporation", 1945 (Box 89)
    - Wahl, Jean. Unsorted writings, undated (Box 89)
    - Walkowitz, Abraham. "Stieglitz - A Pioneer", undated (Box 89)
    - Wallace, Henry A. (Henry Agard). "Text of Vice President Henry A. Wallace Speech at National Citizens Political Action Committee Luncheon", 1944 September 22 (Box 89)
    - Warburg, James P. (James Paul). Put Yourself in Marshall's Place, 1948 (Box 89)
    - Weber, Brom. "Introduction for Prose Writings of Hart Crane", undated (Box 89)
    - Wertham, Frederic. "The Open Mind", 1957 (Box 89)
    - West, Rebecca. "A Reporter at Large", 1947 June 14 (Box 89)
    - Westerfield, Hargis. "Overseas Replacement Center", undated (Box 89)
    - Weston, Edward. "From My Day Book - November 1922" (Box 89)
    - Wheeler, Emily. Untitled, undated (Box 89)
    - Wilhaus, Robin. Poems, undated (Box 89)
    - Williams, Oscar. "Man, Frightening Animal", undated (Box 89)
    - Williams, William Carlos. "Raquel Hélène Rose", 1939 June 29 (Box 89)
    - Willkie, Wendell. "Creed for Americans", 1944 October 15 (Box 89)
    - Winkler, Mr. "Synopsis of a 10,000 Word Pamphlet About the French Situation", 1943 October 28 (Box 89)
    - Wolff, Kurt. "Franz Kafka", undated (Box 89)
    - Woods, Glennyth M. "Death in a Cathedral", undated (Box 89)
    - Woodward, Stanley. "Frick, Breadon Together Quash Anti-Negro Action", undated (Box 89)
    - Wright, Richard. Excerpts from letters, 1945-1948 (Box 89)
    - Wright, Richard. "Psychiatry Goes to Harlem", undated (Box 89)
    - Wright, Richard. "Urban Misery in an American City", undated (Box 89)
    - Wright, Richard. "A World View of the American Negro", undated (Box 89)
    - Wüsten, Johannes. "The Three Nights of Jan Bockelson", undated (Box 89)
    - Yarmolinsky, Avrahm. Untitled, undated (Box 89)
    - York, Ruth. "The Sniper", undated (Box 89)
    - York, Steven. "With Trumpeting and Drum", undated (Box 89)
    - Young, Frederic Harold. "Charles Sanders Peirce", 1945, undated (Box 89)
    - Zigrosser, Carl. "Alfred Stieglitz", undated (Box 89)
    - Zimmer, Heinrich Robert. "The Celtic Romance of the Soul", undated (Box 89)
    - Zylberberg, Helene. "Quelques aspects du tragique kafkeen", undated (Box 89)
    - Unsorted writings, 1941-1944, undated; 6 (Box 89)
  - An American Place Administrative Files
    Chiefly arranged alphabetically.
    - "A" General, 1932-1941, undated (Box 90)
    - "B" General, 1929-1938, undated (Box 90)
    - Bankers Trust Company (New York, N.Y.), 1930-1947 (Box 90)
    - Bank for Savings in the City of New York, 1932-1933, undated (Box 90)
    - Brixey, Richard D., 1929-1932 (Box 90)
    - Butler & Baldwin, 1937-1939 (Box 90)
    - "C" General, 1929-1934, undated (Box 90)
    - Cane, Florence, 1932-1938 (Box 90)
    - Cerf, Bennett A., 1946 July 9 (Box 90)
    - Charking Corporation, 1929-1933 (Box 90)
    - Chemical Bank and Trust Company (New York, N.Y.), 1930; 2 (Box 90)
    - Cohn, Erich & Helene, 1933-1941, undated (Box 90)
    - Cook, Ruth A., 1932-1942, undated (Box 90)
    - Cosgrave, John O'Hara, 1933-1943, undated (Box 90)
    - "D" General, 1932-1947, undated (Box 90)
    - Douglas L. Elliman & Co., 1934-1935, undated (Box 90)
    - Droth, Andrew, 1947-1948, undated (Box 90)
    - "E" General, 1929-1935, undated (Box 90)
    - "F" General, 1930-1938, undated (Box 90)
    - "G" General, 1930-1942 (Box 90)
    - Goodwin, Philip, 1929-1945 (Box 90)
    - "H" General, 1932-1942, undated (Box 90)
    - Harcourt Brace & Company, 1946 September 10 (Box 90)
    - Hartley, Marsden, undated (Box 90)
    - "I" General, 1932-1936 (Box 90)
    - Internal Revenue Service, 1938 (Box 90)
    - Isaacs, Stanley, 1946 December 4 (Box 90)
    - Iselin, O'Donnell, 1929-1930 (Box 90)
    - "J" General, 1932-1941, undated (Box 90)
    - "K" General, 1932, undated (Box 90)
    - Kuhn, Hedwig Stieglitz, 1932-1938 (Box 90)
    - "L" General, 1932-1938, undated (Box 90)
    - Levy, Edgar A., 1929-1932 (Box 90)
    - Levy, Julien, 1932-1934 (Box 90)
    - Liebman, Aline Meyer, 1929-1941 (Box 90)
    - "M" General, 1929-1943 (Box 90)
    - McAlpin, David, 1940-1946 (Box 90)
    - Mitchell May Jr. Company, circa 1940-1947 (Box 90)
    - Morris, Brena, 1932 April 18 (Box 90)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1932-1933 (Box 90)
    - "N" General, 1929-1933 (Box 90)
    - "O" General, 1932-1947 (Box 90)
    - O'Brien, Frances, 1932-1935 (Box 90)
    - "P" General, 1929-1936 (Box 90)
    - Phillips, Duncan, 1947, undated (Box 90)
    - "R" General, 1932-1934, undated (Box 90)
    - Riker & Company, Inc., 1935-1937, undated (Box 90)
    - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1932-1941, undated (Box 90)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1932-1935 (Box 90)
    - Ross, Cary, 1932 May 15 (Box 90)
    - Rothbart, Albert, 1929-1932, undated (Box 90)
    - "S" General, 1932-1935, undated (Box 90)
    - Schulte, David & Carrie, 1929-1942 (Box 90)
    - Stearns, J. H., 1943, undated (Box 90)
    - Stieglitz, Hannah & Albert, 1923-1943, undated (Box 90)
    - Stieglitz, Leopold, 1929-1932 (Box 90)
    - Straus, Flora, 1929-1934, undated (Box 90)
    - Stettheimer, Florine, 1934-1958, undated (Box 90)
    - Strand, Paul & Rebecca, undated (Box 90)
    - "T" General, 1932-1934 (Box 90)
    - "V" General, 1932-1945, undated (Box 90)
    - "W" General, 1929-1946 (Box 90)
    - Webb, Todd, 1946, undated (Box 90)
    - Wertheim, Maurice, 1929-1931 (Box 90)
    - Wm. A. White & Sons, circa 1943-1951 (Box 90)
    - Williams, William Carlos, 1932-1935 (Box 90)
    - Zoler, Emil, 1946 December 5 (Box 90)
    - An American Place - After Stieglitz's death, 1946-1949 (Box 90)
    - Announcement, undated (Box 90)
    - Lease agreements, 1937-1941 (Box 90)
    - Rent fund lists, 1930, undated (Box 90)
    - Rent fund letters, 1932, undated (Box 90)
    - Miscellaneous receipts, 1929-1942 (Box 90)
  - America and Alfred Stieglitz Administrative Files
    - Anderson, Sherwood, 1934 (Box 91)
    - Artists' Gallery (New York, N.Y.), undated (Box 91)
    - Bauer, Catherine, 1934 (Box 91)
    - Bayley, R. Child, 1934-1941 (Box 91)
    - Bragdon, Claude, 1934 (Box 91)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1933 (Box 91)
    - Bryan, W. B. (Wilhelmus Bogart), 1934-1935, undated (Box 91)
    - Bryner, Edna, 1934, undated (Box 91)
    - Cardozo, Benjamin, 1933 (Box 91)
    - Cheney, Sheldon, undated (Box 91)
    - Clurman, Harold, 1934 (Box 91)
    - Copland, Aaron, 1932-1935 (Box 91)
    - Covici, Friede Inc., 1934 August 8 (Box 91)
    - Demuth, Augusta, 1933 (Box 91)
    - Demuth, Charles, 1934 (Box 91)
    - Doubleday, Doran & Company, 1940, undated (Box 91)
    - Dove, Arthur, 1934, undated (Box 91)
    - Duchamp, Marcel, 1934 (Box 91)
    - Flint, Ralph, 1934-1937, undated (Box 91)
    - Frank, Waldo, 1933-1934, undated (Box 91)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1933-1934 (Box 91)
    - Hartley, Marsden, 1934 January 6 (Box 91)
    - Haviland, Paul, 1933-1935 (Box 91)
    - Howard, Evelyn, 1934 (Box 91)
    - John Day Company, 1934, undated (Box 91)
    - Kreymborg, Alfred, 1934 January 9 (Box 91)
    - Literary Guild of America, 1934, undated (Box 91)
    - McCausland, Elizabeth, 1934 February 13 (Box 91)
    - Mellquist, Jerome, 1934 (Box 91)
    - Metcalf, Evelyn Scott, 1933-1936, undated (Box 91)
    - Mumford, Louis, 1934-1935, undated (Box 91)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1932-1935, undated (Box 91)
    - Rugg, Harold, 1932-1935, undated (Box 91)
    - Seligmann, Herbert, 1934 (Box 92)
    - Simon and Schuster, inc., 1934 July 5 (Box 92)
    - Stein, Gertrude, 1934 (Box 92)
    - Strand, Paul, 1933-1934, undated (Box 92)
    - Tofel, Jennings, 1934, undated (Box 92)
    - Walkowitz, Abraham, 1935 (Box 92)
    - Williams, William Carlos, 1934 (Box 92)
    - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1934 (Box 92)
    - Contract and related outlines, 1934-1935 (Box 92)
    - Preliminary notes for America and Alfred Stieglitz, 1934 (Box 92)
  - Twice A Year Administrative Files
    Not arranged in any particular order.
    - Documents - Civil Rights, 1939-1945, undated; 2 (Box 93)
    - Documents - International, 1943-1948, undated (Box 93)
    - Documents - National Affairs, 1945, undated (Box 93)
    - Editorial statements, 1942, undated; 2 (Box 93)
    - Unidentified & anonymous writings, undated; 2 (Box 93)
    - Indian & American writings, 1952, undated (Box 93)
    - Author's list for special issue of Twice A Year, undated (Box 93)
    - Copyright material, 1945-1949, undated (Box 93)
    - Jackson, Robert H. "Closing Address for the United States of America", undated (Box 93)
    - Steinhausen, Herrmann. "Die Zukunft der Freiheit", undated (Box 93)
    - Yale University. Committee on National Policy. "Research Project on Mass Communications", 1948 January 3 (Box 93)
    - Douglas, William O. (William Orville). "Address", 1948 (Box 93)
    - United States. Bureau of the Census, 1945-1947, undated (Box 93)
    - Material relating to appeal for income tax exemption, 1947-1948 (Box 93)
    - Miscellaneous financial & technical material, 1930s-1940s (Box 93)
    - United States Customs Service, 1940 (Box 93)
    - United States Post Office material, 1939-1947 (Box 93)
    - Paper & printing companies, 1947, undated (Box 93)
    - Galleys, undated (Box 93)
    - Twice A Year - Samples & preliminary material, 1938-1948, undated; 17 (Box 93)
    - Miscellaneous lists, questionnaire, and review, undated (Box 93)
    - Program for Igor Stravinsky concert by the Philharmonic -Symphony Society of New York, 1946 (Box 93)
    - Constantin Brancusi exhibition catalogue, undated (Box 93)
    - Newspaper clipping relating to Leon Blum, undated (Box 93)
    - The Griffin, 1954-1955 (Box 93)
    - Reviews and clippings, 1938-1948, undated; 15 (Box 94)
    - Press lists, undated (Box 94)
    - Lists - Foreign countries, undated (Box 94)
    - College material (Issue VIII), undated (Box 94)
    - Lists - Selected bookstores, undated (Box 95)
    - Lists - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 95)
    - Authors - Biographical material, undated (Box 95)
    - Unsorted photographs, undated; 2 (Box 95)
    - Publicity material for issues XIV - XV, undated (Box 95)
    - Proposal for magazine: American Quarterly, undated (Box 95)
- October 1991 Acquisition, 1903-1989; 3; 33.08; 29 boxes
  Much of the material in this accession was created or collected by Dorothy Norman for her writings and publication projects, and consists largely of photostats and typed transcripts (primarily from Beinecke Library's Stieglitz/O'Keeffe Archive, YCAL MSS 85), and typescript drafts of Norman's writings. Included in the accession are copies of correspondence between Alfred Stieglitz and Charles Demuth, Arthur Dove, Katherine S. Drier, Marsden Hartley, Marius de Zayas, and others; original correspondence between Dorothy Norman and Dorothy Brett, Bertram and Gusta Hartman, Mabel Dodge Luhan, John Marin, and others; bibliographic and biographical material relating to Alfred Stieglitz, including notes, research material, anecdotes, and quotes; and printed material relating to painting, photography, Dorothy Norman, and Alfred Stieglitz.
  - Early Stieglitz, related writings, 1926-1980; 24 (Box 96)
  - Alfred Stieglitz stories, undated; 23 (Box 97)
  - Alfred Stieglitz stories, undated; 4 (Box 98)
  - Resume & extracts, undated (Box 98)
  - "Marin sells a Painting", undated (Box 98)
  - "George Grosz and Marin", undated (Box 98)
  - "Marin and a Sermon", undated (Box 98)
  - VIII, Respect for the artist, 1940 + George Grosz, undated (Box 98)
  - Judaism, undated (Box 98)
  - 291, undated (Box 98)
  - About fire, undated (Box 98)
  - "The Hindenburg", undated (Box 98)
  - Stieglitz in Saratoga, undated (Box 98)
  - School days - childhood, undated; 2 (Box 98)
  - Unsorted writings, undated (Box 98)
  - Dorothy Norman quotes, undated; 2 (Box 98)
  - Writings about Stieglitz, undated; 12 (Box 98)
  - Writings about Stieglitz, undated; 8 (Box 99)
  - Alfred Stieglitz - biographical writings, undated; 14 (Box 99)
  - Alfred Stieglitz - Seer ( Aperture ), undated (Box 100)
  - Stieglitz sayings, undated; 2 (Box 100)
  - Dorothy Norman tribute to Alfred Stieglitz, 1956 March (Box 100)
  - Early facts, undated (Box 100)
  - Alfred Stieglitz stories, undated; 19 (Box 100)
  - Alfred Stieglitz - biographical writings, undated; 18 (Box 101)
  - Alfred Stieglitz - biographical writings, undated; 8 (Box 102)
  - Niclas, Yolla. "Alfred Stieglitz - Told to Myself", circa 1948 (Box 102)
  - Excerpts from letters, undated (Box 102)
  - Stieglitz talk at New York Art Center, undated (Box 102)
  - Biography of Alfred Stieglitz - fragments, unpublished material, undated; 6 (Box 102)
  - Biography of Alfred Stieglitz - fragments, unpublished material, undated; 17 (Box 103)
  - Biography of Alfred Stieglitz - fragments, unpublished material, undated; 2 (Box 104)
  - Miscellaneous writings, fragments, undated; 15 (Box 104)
  - Photography and painting, printed material, 1911, undated (Box 104)
  - Photography and painting, printed material, 1913-1937, undated; 17 (Box 105)
  - Photography and painting, printed material, 1903-1983; 23 (Box 106)
  - Research material, undated (Box 106)
  - Lists of operas, plays, etc. seen by Alfred Stieglitz, 1880-1889, undated (Box 106)
  - Photography and painting, printed material, 1905-1966, undated; 11 (Box 106)
  - Printed material, 1969-1971 (Box 107)
  - Georgia O'Keeffe & Alfred Stieglitz, printed material, 1946 (Box 107)
  - Alfred Stieglitz, memorial, 1946 (Box 107)
  - Alfred Stieglitz, printed material, 1947 (Box 107)
  - Photography and painting, printed material, 1948-1977, undated; 10 (Box 107)
  - Picabia, notes, undated (Box 107)
  - Questions, undated (Box 107)
  - 291, Picabia, undated (Box 107)
  - Sadakichi Hartmann Newsletter, 1969-1973 (Box 108)
  - Stieglitz and politics, undated (Box 108)
  - Stieglitz - Parables, undated (Box 108)
  - Carbons of material published in Camera Work, undated (Box 108)
  - Unsorted writings, undated; 3 (Box 108)
  - Printed material, 1908, 1974-1984; 3 (Box 108)
  - Miscellaneous material relating to Stieglitz, undated (Box 108)
  - Notes and printed material, 1947, undated (Box 108)
  - Typescript of printed matter, undated (Box 108)
  - Research material, 1912-1976 (Box 108)
  - Photo Engraving correspondence, undated (Box 108)
  - Alfred Stieglitz letters, transcripts and photostats, undated; 9 (Box 108)
  - The Atlantic Monthly, 1947 (Box 108)
  - Notes on Stieglitz, 1983, undated; 2 (Box 108)